A Guide to the Emmett Russell Price Scrapbooks, 1910-1943
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Emmett Russell Price Scrapbooks, 1910-1943
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1987-011
1.6 cu. ft. 4 boxes
This collection contains the scrapbooks of Emmett Russell Price, professor of Agricultural Journalism at VPI, from 1910-1944. The scrapbooks consist of newspaper clippings about Blacksburg and VPI.
Emmett Russell, Price
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to Newman Library sometime before 1969. The scrapbooks were eventually moved to Special Collections.
Biographical Note
Emmett Russell Price was born in 1874. He was an instructor and professor of Agricultural Journalism at VPI from 1920 until his death in 1944.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the scrapbooks of Emmett Russell Price, professor of Agricultural Journalism at VPI, from 1910-1943. The scrapbooks consist of newspaper clippings about Blacksburg and VPI.
Arrangement
Clippings within scrapbooks are arranged chronologically. The scrapbooks are boxed in chronological order.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Faculty; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); University Archives; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Scrapbook, 1919-1922 (Box-folder 1-1)
- VPI Clippings Book, 1918-1921, 1923-1926 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Mounted Clippings (Box-folder 1-3)
  - 1910
  - 1911
  - 1912
  - 1913
  - 1914
  - 1915
- Scrapbook, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Scrapbook, January 1923- June 1923 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Scrapbook, 1926-1943 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Scrapbook, Extensions, 1926-1943 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Scrapbook, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Scrapbook, 1939-1943 (Box-folder 4-2)